Edward Abbey's Vox Clamantis In Deserto: Some Notes from a Secret Journal production records, 1988-1989
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Edward Abbey's Vox Clamantis In Deserto: Some Notes from a Secret Journal production records, 1988-1989
MS 336
Edward Abbey, 1927-1989
This collection contains the original typescript literary manuscript (ca. 1989) sent to The Rydal Press, the "Memorandum Agreement," correspondence between Clark Kimball and the Abbeys from November 1988 to February 1989, an edited manuscript, various proofs, galleys, and dummies used to prepare the manuscript for publication during 1989, and a production copy of the work.
.75 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Edward Abbey was born in Pennsylvania on 29 January 1927 and died in Tucson, Arizona, on 14 March 1989. He authored seventeen fiction and nonfiction books, and wrote numerous articles and reviews for national and regional publications. Vox Clamantis in Deserto was his last nonfiction work and was "in press" at the time of his death in March 1989. The Rydal Press is represented in this collection by Clark Kimball.
Organization
This collection is organized into two series
Series I: Correspondence, 1988-1989
Series II: Production materials, 1989
Scope and Content Note
Vox Clamantis in Deserto is a collection of fragments from Abbey's journals that he kept "fairly faithfully." In his correspondence with Clark Kimball, Abbey called the work "Vox Clamantis in Deserto: A Selection of Quotes from the Notebooks & Journals of Edward Abbey." In his introduction to the work, Abbey says that the "fragments, or notes, were obviously not chosen at random, but with an eye to propositions and declarations that say something provocative in a minimum number of words."
This collection contains the original typescript literary manuscript (ca. 1989) sent to The Rydal Press, the "Memorandum Agreement," correspondence between Clark Kimball and the Abbeys from November 1988 to February 1989, an edited manuscript, various proofs, galleys, and dummies used to prepare the manuscript for publication during 1989, and a production copy of the work. The book was published in a limited edition of 250 numbered copies, and is available in Special collections, call number PS3551 .B2 V6 1989.
Related Material
Edward Abbey, Papers, 1947-1990, MS 271. Box 22, folders 3 and 4 contain Abbey's copy of agreement, notes, drafts with corrections, and carbons related to Vox Clamantis in Deserto by The Rydal Press.
Access Terms
Abbey, Edward, 1927- -- Philosophy
Abbey, Edward, 1927- -- Archives
Kimball, Clark
Authors, American -- 20th century -- Archives
Manuscripts, American
West (U.S.) -- In literature -- Archival resources
Correspondence
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1988-1989
  - Between Clark Kimball, Edward and Clarke Abbey, 1988-1989 (Copies in box. Originals in vault). 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Production correspondence. 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Production materials, 1989
  - Edited manuscript. 1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Galley proofs. pre July 25, and July 25, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Layout samples, instructions to/from Mina Yamashita. 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Proofs and folded dummies, layouts, and production. June 22, 1989 and July 25, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Proofs and folded dummies, layouts, and production. August 3, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Page proofs. pre July 25 and July 25, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Proofs and folded dummies, layouts, and production. September 15, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Page proofs. September 25, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Final folding dummy, and uncut, unbound signatures. October 22, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Partial blue line and blue-line changes. 1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Text, galley, layout, and sample of publication announcement. 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Original manuscript, with holograph annotations and corrections by Abbey. 1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Vox Clamantis in Deserto production copy, with slipcase. 1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)